cornwall.gov.uk 2006-06-15

# Cornwall County Council - Privacy Policy

Cornwall County Council ("the Council") is committed to preserving the privacy of all visitors to the www.cornwall.gov.uk website ("the Website"). This policy is provided to inform you how we collect, use and protect the information that you provide to us. 

**Privacy Statement**

The Council will ensure that any information it receives will be processed in accordance with the principles contained in the Data Protection Act 1998 and the policy detailed below. This policy only covers the Website and does not cover any third party websites to which links are provided.

**1\. Information that the Council collects from you**

1.1 The Council collects information from you in the following ways:

1.1.1 Information that you provide to the Council

The Website contains feedback forms and questionnaires, which you can complete and return if you wish. The forms may ask for your name and contact details (eg address, telephone number, email address etc). If you choose to complete a questionnaire then you may be asked to provide information on a variety of topics and it is at your discretion, if you choose to do so. The forms will contain notices letting you know why the Council is requesting the information.

You may make an information request and in order to receive a response to your question, you may disclose personal information to the Council. The Council may also collect information about you from messages you post to the Website and emails or letters you send to us. 

1.1.2 Ordering goods and Services

On the Website you can order goods and services and you will be asked to provide contact details and debit/credit card details in order to make a purchase.

**2\. Use of your Information**

2.1 Your information will allow the Council to process and supply any orders for goods and services. It will also enable us to bill you and contact you where necessary regarding any order. 

2.2 The Council may use your information to contact you regarding a request for information or to follow up any feedback forms or questionnaires you may have completed and returned. 

2.3 Your personal information will assist the Council in understanding your needs and interests and the information may be analysed in order to improve and develop the Website and the services provided by the Council as a whole. 

2.4 If the Council wishes to use your personal information for a purpose other than the one for which you provided the information, it will ask for your consent first. 

2.5 The Council will not disclose your information to other organisations or bodies unless required to do so by law. Your information will not be sold, rented or leased without your prior written consent. 

2.6 If you have ordered goods or services, the Council may have to give information to agents or subcontractors in order to process and deliver your order. If this was necessary, the Council would ensure that agents or subcontractors are aware of the obligations in the Data Protection Act 1998 and this Privacy Policy. 

2.7 In the event that the Council transfers management of the Website to a third party, you agree that your information can be transferred to that third party. The Council will ensure that any third party taking over management of the Website will observe the obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998 and this Privacy Policy.

2.8 The Council will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose(s) for which it was collected. Once this purpose has been fulfilled, your personal data will be destroyed and disposed of in accordance in a secure manner. 

2.9 In the event that you no longer consent to the Council processing your personal data, please notify the Council in writing.

**3\. Security**

3.1 Any information that you send to the Website using the questionnaires, forms or via email will not be sent using a secure transmission method. It is important that you are aware that any information which is sent via the internet can be intercepted or lost and may be read by others. 

3.2 The Council has put into place the appropriate technological procedures and practices to protect the information which is collected using the Website.

3.3 The Council has ensured that any members of staff or agents processing personal information on behalf of the Council are aware of their obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998 and this Privacy Policy. 

3.4 The Website contains a shopping area, where you can purchase goods and services online. The shopping area is a secure site and is certificated as secure for financial transactions. The padlock symbol will be visible at the bottom of your screen whilst you are in the secure site.

**4\. Offensive Material and Crime Prevention**

4.1 In accordance with the Terms and Conditions of the Website, you are not permitted to post or send any offensive or inappropriate material or information to the Website. In the event that you breach this term, the Council may use your personal information to take action against you to prevent further breaches of this term.

4.2 The Council has systems in place to protect itself, the community and users of its Website against fraud and other crimes. The Council may use your personal information to detect and prevent crime and may disclose your information to the police and fraud prevention agencies, where it suspects that you have or are going to commit a crime.

**5\. Users under 16**

5.1 If you are aged under 16, you must get permission from your parents before providing the Council with any personal information. The Council may check that you have obtained consent and will not accept your personal information if you have not done so. 

5.2 The Website is not aimed at children, however, if in the future the Council does decide to develop areas within the Website for children, it will put into place a special privacy policy aimed at children. 

**7\. Access to your personal information**

7.1 You have the right to request a copy of the personal information which the Council holds about you and you also have the right to request that the information is rectified if it is inaccurate. 

7.2 If you would like to request a copy of your personal information, please follow this link to the Data Protection area which sets out the County Council's procedure for dealing with your request. The Council is permitted to charge you a fee of £10 and has 40 days in which to process your request.

7.3 The Council reserves the right to refuse to comply with your request for disclosure of information, but will only do so when it is permitted under the Data Protection Act 1998 and will give you the reasons for refusal.

**8\. Feedback, Complaints or Disputes**

8.1 If you have any comments or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact [The Data Protection Officer](mailto:dataprotection@cornwall.gov.uk?subject=feedback%20from%20the%20Cornwall%20County%20Council%20web%20site). You may also write to: The Data Protection Officer, Cornwall County Council, New County Hall, Treyew Road, Truro, Cornwall, TR1 3AY. 

8.2 If you have any general feedback or comments regarding the Website, please email [the Council's web manager](mailto:webmanager@cornwall.gov.uk?subject=feedback%20from%20the%20Council%27s%20web%20site) or use the Council's feedback form
